大家安静一下
Everybody, shh, shh,S
中央公园很荣幸为各位介绍
Central Park is proud to present the music of
菲比·布菲小姐的音乐演出
Miss Phoebe Buffay.
大家好  首先我想演唱一首有关
Hi. Um, I want to start with a song that is about that moment
顿悟人生那一刻的歌
when you suddenly realize what life is all about.
开始咯
OK, here we go.
非常感谢
OK, thank you very much.
怎么
What?
这下可好
Oh, great.
真是太
This is just...
这简直是酷毙了
Wow, this is so cool, you guys.
全城大停电
The entire city is blacked out!
我妈说是整个布鲁克林
Mom says it's all of Manhattan,
外加部份曼哈顿和皇后区
parts of Brooklyn and Queens,
不知何时恢复电力
and they have no idea when it's coming back on.
这可真是大停电
Wow, you guys, this is big.
裤子和毛衣  为什么  妈
Pants and a sweater? Why, mom?
停电我能去见谁
Who am I gonna meet in a blackout?
电力公司的人  趁火打劫的单身汉吗
Power company guys? Eligible looters?
这话题以后再聊  好吗
Could we talk about this later? OK.
电话能借我吗
Can I borrow the phone?
我想打回住处  确定我祖母是否安好
I want to call my apartment and check on my grandma.
我的电话几号
What's my number?
我从未给自己打过电话
Well, I never call me.
天啊  是她  维多利亚秘密的模特儿
Oh my God, it's that Victoria's Secret model.
叫古达克的
Something... something Goodacre.
-妈  我是吉尔  -没错  吉尔·古达克
- Hi Mom, it's Jill. - She's right, it's Jill. Jill Goodacre.
没想到我和吉尔同时被困在提款机室
I am trapped in an ATM vestibule with Jill Goodacre!
是前厅  还是正厅
Is it a vestibule? Maybe it's an atrium.
那才是值得注意的对象  笨蛋
Oh, yeah, that is the part to focus on, you idiot!
对  我没事只是被困在银行提款机室
Yeah, I'm fine. I'm just stuck at the bank, in an ATM vestibule.
吉尔说前厅
Jill says vestibule...
那我也当做是前厅好了
I'm going with vestibule.
我没事  不  旁边有人
I'm fine. No, I'm not alone...
我不认识  某人
I don't know, some guy.
某人  某人
Oh! Some guy. Some guy.
吉尔  我昨晚看见你和某人在一起
'Hey Jill, I saw you with some guy last night.
没错  他是某人
Yes, he was some guy.
各位
Hi everyone.
今晚主持停电晚会的是罗比·崔比阿尼
And officiating at tonight's blackout, is Rabbi Tribbiani.
钱德勒以前的室友是犹太人
Well, Chandler's old roomate was Jewish,
我们只剩这些蜡烛
and these are the only candles we have, so...
祝各位光明节快乐
Happy Chanukah, everyone.
瞧  丑陋裸男点了一堆蜡烛
Eww, look. Ugly Naked Guy lit a bunch of candles.
一定很痛
That had to hurt!
好吧好吧  已过了14分30秒
Alright, alright, alright. It's been fourteen and a half minutes
你却连一字也没说
and you still have not said one word.
争气点  打破沉闷
Oh God, do something. Just make contact,
微笑
Smile!
效果不错
There you go!
你绝对是在吓她
You're definitely scaring here.
你需要给别人打电话吗
Would you like to call somebody?
好啊  高中时代有三百个同学
Yeah, about 300 guys I went to high school with.
谢了
Yeah, thanks.
-喂  -是我
- Hello? - Hey, it's me.
是钱德勒
It's Chandler!
-你好吗  -我还好
- Are you OK? - Yeah, I'm fine.
我和吉尔·古达克
I'm trappd in an ATM vestibule
被困在提款机室
wth Jill Goodacre
什么
What?
我和吉尔·古达克
I'm trappd... in an ATM vestibule...
被困在提款机室
wth Jill Goodacre!
我听不懂你在说什么
I have no idea what you just said.
叫乔伊听电话
Put Joey on the phone.
怎么了
What's up man?
我和吉尔·古达克
I'm trppd... in an ATM vestibule...
被困在提款机室
wth Jill Goodacre.
噢  我的天那
Oh my God!
他和吉尔·古达克被困在提款机室
He's trapped in an ATM vestibule with Jill Goodacre!
钱德勒  听着
Chandler, listen.
别以为我没这个念头
Yeah, like that thought never entered my mind.
换人  快
Alright, somebody.
好吧  换我
OK, I'll go.
大四  在台球桌上
OK, senior year of college... on a pool table.
这就是我妹啦
That's my sister.
我最奇怪的地方是在
OK... my weirdest place would have to be...
纽约市立图书馆
the women's room on the second floor of
二楼女厕所
the New York CIty public library.
拜托  你去图书馆干什么
Oh my God! What were you doing in a library?
菲比  你呢
Pheebs, what about you?
密尔瓦基市
Oh... Milwaukee.
罗斯
Um... Ross?
迪士尼  1989年  小小世界
Disneyland, 1989, 'It's a Small World After All.'
不可能
No way!
机器故障
The ride broke down.
所以我和卡罗尔就到
So, Carol and I went behind
荷兰机器娃娃后面
a couple of those mechanical Dutch children...
一会机器修好了
then they fixed the ride,
从此他们禁止我们再到奇幻王国去
and we were asked never to return to the Magic Kingdom.
-瑞秋呢  -拜托  我说过了
- Oh, Rachel. - Oh come on, I already went.
-你才没那  -快点告诉我们
- You did not go! - Come on.
好吧  最奇怪的地方是
Oh, alright. The weirdest place would have to be...
床脚
oh, the foot of the bed.
注意  我们今晚的赢家出现了
Step back. We have a winner!
我从没有那种关系  也没那种激情冲动
I just never had a relationship with that kind of passion,
你知道么  那种在主题公园中央
you know, where you have to have somebody right there,
升腾起来的欲火难耐的心情
in the middle of a theme park.
当时只有这件事可做
Well, it was the only thing to do there that didn't have a line.
就是这个意思
There, well, see?
巴瑞连在打迷你高尔夫时也不肯亲我
Barry wouldn't even kiss me on a miniature golf course.
少来
Come on.
真的  他说这样会耽误后面的人
No, he said we were holding up the people behind us.
你逃婚的原因是
And you didn't marry him because...?
你有没有觉得有一种人会一辈子
I mean, do you think there are people
都庸庸碌碌从未拥有过某种
who go through life never having that kind of...
也许吧
Probably.
但是我得告诉你
But you know, I'll tell you something.
-我们高估了恋爱中的激情  -是吗
- Passion is way overrated. - Yeah right.
真的  激情最终会消退
It is. Eventually, it kind of... burns out.
但双方仍保有信赖  安全感和
But hopefully, what you're left with is trust, and security, and...
以我前妻为例  女同志主义
well, in the case of my ex-wife, lesbianism.
因此  那些缺乏激情之人
So, you know, for all of those people who miss out on
还有其他可取之处
that passion... thing, there's all that other good stuff.
-明白  -但我想你不是那种人
- OK. - But, um... I don't think that's going to be you.
你也觉得不是
You don't.
我觉得  你的未来将充满激情
Uh-uh. See, I see.... big passion in your future.
-真的吗  -嗯
- Really? - Mmmm.
-真的吗  -真的
-You do? - I do.
罗斯  你真是太了不起了
Oh Ross, you're so great.
你别妄想了
It's never gonna happen.
什么
What?
你和瑞秋
You and Rachel.
为什么
Why not?
因为你拖拖拉拉迟迟不肯行动
Because you waited too long to make your move,
现在只能待在"朋友区"
and now you're in the friend zone.
不不不  我没在朋友区
No, no, no. I'm not in the zone.
罗斯  你是朋友区主席
Ross, you're mayor of the zone.
我这是慢慢来  行吗
I'm taking my time, alright?
我正在为以后铺路
I'm laying the groundwork.
每一天  我都会更接近
Yeah. I mean, every day I get just a little bit closer to...
变成神父
Priesthood!
罗斯  她根本不知道你在想什么
Look Ross, I'm telling you, she has no idea what you're thinking.
如果再不快点约她出去
If you don't ask her out soon
你将困在朋友区  永世不得翻身
you're going to end up stuck in the zone forever.
我会的  我只是在等恰当的时机
I will, I will. See, I'm waiting for the right moment.
干吗  什么  现在吗
What? What, now?
对哦
Yeeeeaaaahhh!
你犹豫个什么劲儿啊
What's messing you up?
美酒  烛光  月光
The wine? The candles? The moonlight?
你只需走到她面前说
You've just got to go up to her and say,
瑞秋  我想
'Rachel, I think that...'
你在嘘什么
What are you shushing?
我们嘘  是因为我们正在听
We're shushing... because... we're trying to hear something.
听什么
What?
难道你没听见
Don't you hear that?
听见没
See?
想来片口香糖吗
Would you like some gum?
无糖的吗
Um, is it sugarless?
抱歉  不是
Sorry, it's not.
不  谢了
Oh, then no thanks.
你在搞什么东西
What the hell was that?
切记  吉尔·古达克请你吃口香糖你就吃
Mental note : If Jill Goodacre offers you gum, you take it.
她叫你吃动物死尸  你也得吃
If she offers you mangled animal carcass, you take it.
*纽约大停电*
*New York City has no power,*
*牛奶变酸*
*and the milk is getting sour.*
*不过没什么好怕的*
*But to me it is not scary,*
*因为我不吃奶制品*
*because I stay away from dairy*
-我要去了  -你决定啦
- OK, here goes. - Are you going to do it?
我决定了
I'm going to do it.
需要帮助吗
Do you want any help?
如果你想当电灯泡  你就死定了
You come out there, you're a dead man.
祝你幸运
Good luck, man.
-你要去哪里  -外面
- Hey, where are you going? - Outside.
不行  你不能去外面
You can't go out there.
为什么
Why not?
因为有理由
Because of... the reason.
什么理由
And that would be?
我  不能告诉你
I, um, can't tell you.-
乔伊  到底怎么了
Joey, what's going on?
好吧  但你得答应我
OK, you've got to promise that
不会告诉罗斯是我说的
you'll never, ever tell Ross that I told you.
说什么
About what?
他正在准备你的生日派对
He's planning your birthday party.
天啊  我爱他
Oh my God! I love him!
你最好装成一副吃惊的样子
You'd better act surprised.-
-装什么  -我的生日派对
- About what? - My surprise party!
-什么派对  -少装蒜了
- What surprise party? - Oh stop it.
乔伊已经告诉我了
Joey already told me.
他没有告诉我
Well, he didn't tell me.
别看我  这是罗斯的主意
Hey, don't look at me. This is Ross's thing.
每次都这样
This is so typical.
我总是最后知道的人
I'm always the last one to know everything.
你不是  我们都有告诉你
No, you are not. We tell you stuff.
才怪  钱德勒在动物园被孔雀咬
Yuh-huh! I was the last one to know
我是最后知道的人
when Chandler got bitten by the peacock at the zoo.
乔伊刚搬来时你对他有意思
I was the last one to know when you had a crush on Joey
我也是最后知道
when he was moving in.
什么
What?
看来我是倒数第二知道的
Looks like I was second to last.
感觉好好
Hmmm... this is so nice.
我有个问题
OK, I have a question. .
实际上  也谈不上是问题
Well, actually, it's not so much a question as..
更类似于好奇心
more of a general wondering... ment
是这样的
OK. Here goes.
这些日子以来我一直想
For a while now, I've been wanting to, um....
对  没错
Yes, yes, that's right...
瞧那只小猫  -什么
- Oh, look at the little cat!  - What? Ow!
*我站在世界之巅*
*I'm on top of the world,*
*俯瞰芸芸丛生  却只找到一种解释*
*looking down on creation and the only explanation I can find,*
消炎喷雾而已  不会痛的
This is just Bactine. It won't hurt.
对不起  那是蜡油
Sorry, that was wax.
可怜的小猫快吓死了
Oh, poor little Tooty is scared to death.
我们得找到它的主人
We should find his owner.
我们干吗不直接将它放在走廊里
Why don't we just put 'poor little Tooty' out in the hall?
正在大停电  它会被踩死的
During a blackout? He'd get trampled!-
是吗
Yeah?
考虑之后  口香糖是绝佳的选择
You know, on second thought, gum would be perfection.
口香糖是绝佳的选择
'Gum would be perfection'?,'
'Gum would be perfection.'
我大可说"口香糖也不错"
Could have said 'gum would be nice,'
或是"我也来一片"
or 'I'll have a stick"
不行不行
but no, no, no, no.
"口香糖是绝佳的选择"就可以了
For me, gum is perfection.
我真鄙视我自己
I loathe myself.
不  孟德斯家讨厌一切活物
Oh no, the Mendels, they hate all living things,
你好  我们刚捡到这只猫
Hi. We just found this cat
现在正在找它的主人
and we're looking for the owner.
对  猫是我的
Er, yeah, it's mine.
可是它似乎很讨厌你
He seems to hate you.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
确定  猫是我的  把猫给我
Yeah, it's my cat. Give me my cat.
等等  它叫什么名字
Wait a minute. What's his name?
鲍勃钮扣
Ehhhh... B-Buttons.-
Bob Buttons?
过来  鲍勃钮扣  来  鲍勃钮扣
Mmm. Bob Buttons. Here, Bob Buttons.
你真是个大坏蛋
Oooh! You are a very bad man!
你们欠我一只猫
You owe me a cat.
小猫咪  过来  小猫咪
Here, kitty-kitty. Here kitty-kitty.
你上哪儿去了  小猫咪  小猫咪
Where did you go, little kitty-kitty-kitty...
小猫咪  小猫咪  过来  小猫咪
Kitty, kitty, kitty. Come here, kitty, kitty.
-嗨  -晚上好[意大利语]
- Hi. - Buona sera.
来吧  幸运六
Come on. Lucky sixes....
各位  他是保罗  保罗
Everybody, this is Paolo. Paolo,
我来向你介绍我的朋友
I want you to meet my friends.
这位是莫妮卡
This is Monica.
这位是乔伊
And Joey....
还有罗斯
And Ross.
他不太会讲英语
He doesn't speak much English.
-地产大亨  -不错嘛
- Monopoly! - Look at that!
那么  保罗是哪里人
So, um... where did Paolo come from?
意大利吧  我猜
Oh... Italy, I think.
不  我是指今晚
No, I mean tonight,
这栋公寓  突然闯入我们的生活
in the building. Suddenly. Into our lives.
那只猫  那只猫是保罗的
Well, the cat... the cat turned out to be Paolo's cat!
是不是很有意思
Is that funny?
真有意思  而且瑞秋还不断摸他
That, that is funny... and Rachel keeps touching him.
我找遍了整栋公寓
Alright. I looked all over the building
但就是找不到猫
and I couldn't find the kitty anywhere.
我找到了  是保罗的猫
Oh, I found him. He was Paolo's cat.
瞧  我又是最后一个知道的
Ah! Well! There you go! Last to know again!
由于没人告诉我  我猜他就是保罗吧
And I'm guessing... since nobody told me... this is Paolo.
保罗  她叫菲比
Ah, Paolo, this is Phoebe.
没错
You betcha!
看一下  下一步是什么  吹泡泡
Ah, let's see. What next? Blow a bubble.
吹泡泡好  展现
A bubble's good. It's got a...
大男孩的魅力  很顽皮
boyish charm, it's impish.
来吧
Here we go.
吹得好啊  小鬼  不要紧
Nice going, imp. OK, it's OK.
我只需把手伸过去
All I need to do is reach over
将它放回口中
and put it in my mouth.
救得好
Good save!
现在我已重回轨道
We're back on track,
而且还嚼着别人的口香糖
and I'm...chewing someone else's gum.
这不是我的口香糖
This is not my gum.
天哪天哪  现在你还被噎到了
Oh my God! Oh my God! And now you're choking.
你没事吧
Are you alright?
天呀  你噎到了
My God, you're choking!
感觉好点没
That better?
好多了
Yes.
谢谢  刚才真是
Thank you. That was... that was....
绝佳的选择
Perfection?
他讲什么呢  那么好笑
Wha-What did he say that was so funny?
我完全搞不懂
I have absolutely no idea.
女人都这样
That's... that's classic.
天啊  我在干什么  我在干什么啊
Oh my God, you guys, what am I doing? What am I doing?
这太不像我了
This is so un-me!
不介意的话我要上了
If you want, I'll do it.
我知道
I know,
我只想咬他的下嘴唇
I just want to bite his bottom lip.
但我不会的
But I won't.
上帝啊  他第一次对我微笑时
God, the first time he smiled at me...
那三秒钟比我和巴瑞在百慕达
those three seconds were more exciting than
待三个礼拜还令我兴奋
three weeks in Bermuda with Barry.
你骑摩托车吗
You know, did you ride mopeds?
因为我听说
Because I've heard...
好吧  不是聊这个的时候  明白
Oh, I see... it's not about that right now. OK.
我知道这样很肤浅
Y'know, I know it's totally superficial
而且我们毫无共通点
and we have absolutely nothing in common,
连语言也不通但上帝哟
and we don't even speak the same language but Goooooooddddddd....
保罗
Paolo.
罗斯
Hi.Ross!
听着
Listen. Um,
listen.um,
有件事你该知道
Something you should... know...
瑞秋和我
Rachel and I...
有那么点意思
we're kind of a thing.
意思
Thing?
你俩做爱了
Ah, you... have the sex?
没
No,
没没  技术上而言还没做爱
no, no. Technically the... sex is not... being had,
但是呢  这不是重点
but that's... see, that's not the point.
重点是
See, um, the point is that...
瑞秋和我
Rachel and I
应该在一起
should be, er, together.
而如果你横插一脚在
You know, and if you get in the.... um...
床上
Bed?
不是  我不是指那个
No, that's not where I was going.
如果你让我们无法成一对
Er, if you get in the... way, of us becoming a thing,
我会非常难过
then I would be, well, very sad.
你懂一点英文
So you do know a little English.
会一点
Poco... a leetle.
对  你懂什么叫大骗子吗
Do you know the word crap weasel?
-不懂  -有意思
- No. - That's funny,
因为你就是  你是个超级大骗子
because you know, you are a huge crap weasel!
钱德勒  我们已玩了一小时
Chandler, we've been here for an hour doing this!
很简单的  准备好没
Now watch, it's easy. OK. Ready?
试试看
Try it.
不  你该拍一下
No, you've got to whip it.
看看看  最后一根蜡烛就要燃尽
Oh, look look look. The last candle's about to burn out.
负46  负47  负48
negative 46, negative 47, negative 48
-谢天谢地  -谢谢啊
- Thank you. - Thanks.
一点光都没有  有点恐怖
Kinda... spooky without any lights.
听着听着  我这个最逼真
OK, guys, guys? I have the definitive one
罗斯  现在表白貌似不太是时候
Hey Ross. This probably isn't the best time to bring it up,
但你得为莫妮卡开个派对
but you have to throw a party for Monica.
-玩得真开心  -是啊
- Well, this has been fun. - Yes.
对  谢谢你将手机借我用
Yes, thanks for letting me use your phone...
并救了我的命
and for saving my life.
再见了  钱德勒
Well, goodbye Chandler.
这次的停电经历很欢乐
I had a great blackout.
再见
See ya.
我的账户号码是7143457
Hi, um, I'm account number 7143457.
我不知道你有没有录到
And, uh, I don't know if you got any of that,
但我想要这卷录影带的拷贝
but I would really like a copy of the tape.